<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on AsOpposedToWhat.com</title>
    <link>https://asopposedtowhat.com/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on AsOpposedToWhat.com</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Copyright {year} Steve Isaacson</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2024 12:54:59 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://asopposedtowhat.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Cancerism</title>
      <link>https://asopposedtowhat.com/posts/cancerism/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2024 12:54:59 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://asopposedtowhat.com/posts/cancerism/</guid>
      <description>Imagine for a moment that in the past, innocent people were unfairly given cancer. Imagine that it was bad and really unfair.&#xA;We know that if this were true, that it&amp;rsquo;s a terrible thing to do.&#xA;Further suppose that the effects of these past cancers in some way still affects society today. How best to deal with these lingering effects?&#xA;What we could do, in order to &amp;lsquo;balance out&amp;rsquo; the past injustice, is give out more cancer today, but to new and different innocents.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Death of a Species</title>
      <link>https://asopposedtowhat.com/posts/death-of-a-species/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jan 2024 09:36:49 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://asopposedtowhat.com/posts/death-of-a-species/</guid>
      <description>What would happen if you woke up tomorrow and discovered that the only males left in the world were cisgender1 men, and the only females left in the world were transgender2 women? What would happen to the human species?&#xA;What would happen is that our species would eventually die out. It would be the end of civilization.&#xA;Our species would eventually die out because humans are animals that propagate via sexual reproduction, and transgender women, regardless of how they identify or appear to the world, are still, biologically speaking, males.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>When stupid mixes with stupid</title>
      <link>https://asopposedtowhat.com/posts/stupid_mixed_with_stupid/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jan 2024 18:21:31 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://asopposedtowhat.com/posts/stupid_mixed_with_stupid/</guid>
      <description>On page two of my morning newspaper I saw a story titled, &amp;ldquo;[The famous musical] &amp;lsquo;Oklahoma!&amp;rsquo; to debut after trans student reinstated.&amp;rdquo;1&#xA;The story is about a high school in Texas that was thrust into the national spotlight because of a peculiar situation created by the intersection of two stupid ideas.&#xA;The first stupid idea was the school&amp;rsquo;s enactment of a new policy that stipulated that school stage productions can only have male actors playing male roles, and only female actors playing female roles.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Back in the Day</title>
      <link>https://asopposedtowhat.com/posts/back-in-the-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Nov 2023 20:09:26 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://asopposedtowhat.com/posts/back-in-the-day/</guid>
      <description>Back in the day, Sneed liked to carry a pumpkin. He never really explained why, but I guess his weirdness wore off on me because I developed an equally bizarre hankering for zucchinis.&#xA;Once we walked into a Denny&amp;rsquo;s restaurant and the waitress asked if I had a cucumber in my pocket.&#xA;&amp;ldquo;No,&amp;rdquo; I said, &amp;ldquo;it&amp;rsquo;s a zucchini. Are you happy to see me?&amp;rdquo;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Does my gerbil have a gender?</title>
      <link>https://asopposedtowhat.com/posts/gerbil-gender/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Feb 2023 16:50:56 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://asopposedtowhat.com/posts/gerbil-gender/</guid>
      <description>The short answer is: No. Gerbils are animals that have a sex, but not a gender.&#xA;Sex &amp;ldquo;Sex is a trait that determines an individual&amp;rsquo;s reproductive function, male or female, in animals and plants that propagate their species through sexual reproduction. The type of gametes produced by an organism defines its sex. Commonly in plants and animals, male organisms produce smaller gametes (sperm) while female organisms produce larger gametes (ova, or egg cells).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The bias-detecting Eye of Sauron</title>
      <link>https://asopposedtowhat.com/posts/biased-tax-audits/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2023 12:08:41 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://asopposedtowhat.com/posts/biased-tax-audits/</guid>
      <description>A team of economic experts1 recently concluded that the computer algorithms used by the Internal Revenue Service (IRS) are structurally biased against Blacks, even though no racial information is contained in a tax return.&#xA;How can anyone, let alone a computer algorithm, be biased if there&amp;rsquo;s nothing to be biased about?&#xA;One explanation is that the algorithms were primarily designed to analyze easy-to-process tax returns. For example, returns that do not include business income.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On &#39;Respecting&#39; Personal Pronouns</title>
      <link>https://asopposedtowhat.com/posts/personal-pronoun-respect/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2023 11:25:44 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://asopposedtowhat.com/posts/personal-pronoun-respect/</guid>
      <description>If I&amp;rsquo;m asked, for example, to respect gay marriage (even if it&amp;rsquo;s against my religious views) or to be kind and pay for sidewalk curb cuts for the handicapped, those requests don&amp;rsquo;t require me to change my behaviour (except for paying taxes for something I might disagree with). But asking me to &amp;lsquo;respect&amp;rsquo; your personal pronouns does require me to act differently.&#xA;It changes the way I speak; it changes the words that I use.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Writing Is Work</title>
      <link>https://asopposedtowhat.com/posts/writing-is-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2022 06:41:42 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://asopposedtowhat.com/posts/writing-is-work/</guid>
      <description>What is your writing process? The first thing is, you&amp;rsquo;ve got something to say. It starts with an idea you want to express, or a question you want to answer.&#xA;But that&amp;rsquo;s only the beginning.&#xA;The hard part is not expressing ideas or answering questions. Or even having something to say. Anyone can fill a blank page with words. Just transcribe your train of thought, it never stops.&#xA;The hard part is putting words on paper in such a way that the reader understands the idea you want to express, in such a way that the reader understands the question you want to answer (and your answer).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Do billiard balls (or humans) have free will?</title>
      <link>https://asopposedtowhat.com/posts/billiard-balls/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Mar 2022 11:28:15 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://asopposedtowhat.com/posts/billiard-balls/</guid>
      <description>Billiard balls If free will is &amp;ldquo;the power of acting without the constraint of necessity or fate; the ability to act at one&amp;rsquo;s own discretion,&amp;rdquo; then it&amp;rsquo;s pretty clear that billiard balls do not have free will.&#xA;Why? Because obviously when the cue ball strikes the eight ball, the eight ball doesn&amp;rsquo;t decide to bounce left or right. The eight ball doesn&amp;rsquo;t decide anything at all. Its movement is wholly constrained by physics.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My TransGentry Newfound Pronouns</title>
      <link>https://asopposedtowhat.com/posts/trans-gentry-newfound-pronouns/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Feb 2022 11:35:20 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://asopposedtowhat.com/posts/trans-gentry-newfound-pronouns/</guid>
      <description>In these socially enlightened times it seems everyone and his brother is coming out with a new identity. We&amp;rsquo;re rife with transformations. Who knew?&#xA;But why now? Have we always had men who are really women and women who are really men, and just not noticed? Apparently so. And woe to any bigot or non-woke individual who speaks out contrariwise.&#xA;Most people agree that adults have the right to transform themselves in a way that makes their life better.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What would COVID say?</title>
      <link>https://asopposedtowhat.com/posts/what-would-covid-say/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Dec 2021 17:58:21 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://asopposedtowhat.com/posts/what-would-covid-say/</guid>
      <description>COVID-19: Hello and welcome everyone (and I do mean everyone). Covid here, along with Polio&amp;hellip;&#xA;POLIO: Hi, folks. I don&amp;rsquo;t get out much now, it&amp;rsquo;s a treat for me just to be here.&#xA;COVID-19: We&amp;rsquo;re here on behalf of viruses everywhere to say thanks. Thanks to anti-masker-vaxxers for making this pandemic (and my submicroscopic existence) such a success.&#xA;POLIO: Go&amp;hellip; team!&#xA;COVID-19: We recently reached our goal of 700,000 deaths&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The parable of the squirrel</title>
      <link>https://asopposedtowhat.com/posts/parable-of-the-squirrel/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Aug 2021 16:31:59 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://asopposedtowhat.com/posts/parable-of-the-squirrel/</guid>
      <description>(aka A ferocious metaphysical dispute1) Some time ago, being with a camping party in the mountains, I returned from a solitary ramble to find everyone engaged in a ferocious metaphysical dispute.&#xA;The focus of the dispute was a squirrel &amp;ndash; a live squirrel supposed to be clinging to one side of a tree-trunk; while over against the opposite side of the tree, a man was imagined to stand.&#xA;The man knows the squirrel is on the other side of the tree-trunk, but he can&amp;rsquo;t see the squirrel.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Half-Truths</title>
      <link>https://asopposedtowhat.com/posts/half-truths/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jul 2021 15:53:34 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://asopposedtowhat.com/posts/half-truths/</guid>
      <description>When You Assume When you assume you make an ass out of you and me.1 And yet, before it even makes sense to utter that statement, I assume you understand English; I assume that you can hear me, that you&amp;rsquo;re listening, that you&amp;rsquo;re not an asshat. Don&amp;rsquo;t fix it if it ain&amp;rsquo;t broke Don&amp;rsquo;t fix it if it ain&amp;rsquo;t broke — unless it&amp;rsquo;s one of those problems that if you fix it now it may save you a lot of extra work later on.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
