<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on AsOpposedToWhat.com</title>
    <link>https://asopposedtowhat.com/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on AsOpposedToWhat.com</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Copyright {year} Steve Isaacson</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 26 Feb 2022 16:50:56 -0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://asopposedtowhat.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Does my gerbil have a gender?</title>
      <link>https://asopposedtowhat.com/posts/gerbil-gender/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Feb 2022 16:50:56 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://asopposedtowhat.com/posts/gerbil-gender/</guid>
      <description>The short answer is No.
Gerbils are animals that have a sex, but not a gender.
Sex &amp;ldquo;Sex is a trait that determines an individual&amp;rsquo;s reproductive function, male or female, in animals and plants that propagate their species through sexual reproduction. The type of gametes produced by an organism defines its sex. Commonly in plants and animals, male organisms produce smaller gametes (spermatozoa, sperm) while female organisms produce larger gametes (ova, often called egg cells).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coming Out TransGentry</title>
      <link>https://asopposedtowhat.com/posts/trans-gentry/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Feb 2022 11:35:20 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://asopposedtowhat.com/posts/trans-gentry/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s socially acceptable to come out &amp;lsquo;trans&amp;rsquo; nowadays, so here goes, I&amp;rsquo;m coming out.
But first I want to say that I&amp;rsquo;m not proud of the fact that I&amp;rsquo;ve waited this long to come out, but I&amp;rsquo;m also not embarrassed &amp;ndash; at least not any longer. If postmodernism has taught us anything, it&amp;rsquo;s taught us that we can be whoever we say we are and fuck-you bigots if you disagree.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What would COVID say?</title>
      <link>https://asopposedtowhat.com/posts/what-would-covid-say/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Dec 2021 17:58:21 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://asopposedtowhat.com/posts/what-would-covid-say/</guid>
      <description>COVID-19: Hello and welcome everyone (and I do mean everyone). Covid here, along with Polio&amp;hellip;
POLIO: Hi, folks. I don&amp;rsquo;t get out much now, it&amp;rsquo;s a treat for me just to be here.
COVID-19: We&amp;rsquo;re here on behalf of viruses everywhere to say thanks. Thanks to anti-masker-vaxxers for making this pandemic (and my submicroscopic existence) such a success.
POLIO: Go&amp;hellip; team!
COVID-19: We recently reached our goal of 700,000 deaths&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The parable of the squirrel</title>
      <link>https://asopposedtowhat.com/posts/parable-of-the-squirrel/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Aug 2021 16:31:59 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://asopposedtowhat.com/posts/parable-of-the-squirrel/</guid>
      <description>aka A ferocious metaphysical dispute Some time ago, being with a camping party in the mountains, I returned from a solitary ramble to find everyone engaged in a ferocious metaphysical dispute.
The focus of the dispute was a squirrel &amp;ndash; a live squirrel supposed to be clinging to one side of a tree-trunk; while over against the opposite side of the tree, a man was imagined to stand.
The man knows the squirrel is on the other side of the tree-trunk, but he can&amp;rsquo;t see the squirrel.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Half-Truths</title>
      <link>https://asopposedtowhat.com/posts/half-truths/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jul 2021 15:53:34 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://asopposedtowhat.com/posts/half-truths/</guid>
      <description>When You Assume  When you assume you make an ass out of you and me. [ASS U ME] — and yet, before it even makes sense to utter that statment, I assume you understand English; I assume that you can hear me, that you&amp;rsquo;re listening, that you&amp;rsquo;re not an asshat.  Too many cooks  Two many cooks spoil the broth — except, when two heads are better than one.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
